Better late than never.
The 40 Year Old Virgin is a comedy, romance film directed by Judd Apatow.
Andy Stitzer has a pleasant life with a nice apartment and a
job stamping invoices at an electronics store.
But at age 40, there's one thing Andy hasn't done, and it's really bothering
his sex-obsessed male co-workers: Andy is still a virgin.
Determined to help Andy get laid, the guys make it
their mission to de-virginize him.
But it all seems hopeless until Andy meets small
business owner Trish, a single mom.
Andy Stitzer, played by Steve Carell.
Trish Piedmont, played by Catherine Keener.
David, played by Paul Rudd.
Jay, played by Romany Malco.
Cal, played by Seth Rogen.
Beth, played by Elizabeth Banks.
The 40-Year-Old Virgin is a 2005 American romantic comedy film directed by Judd Apatow (in his feature
directorial debut), who produced the film with Clayton Townsend and Shauna Robertson.
It features Steve Carell as the titular 40-year-old virgin
Andy, an employee at an electronics store.
Paul Rudd, Romany Malco, and Seth Rogen play co-workers who resolve to help him lose his
virginity, and Catherine Keener stars as Andy's love interest, Trish.
Watching Carell's performance in Anchorman: The Legend of Ron Burgundy (2004) inspired Apatow to cast
him in the lead role for the film, and they wrote The 40-Year-Old Virgin together.
It was based on a sketch Carell created with The Second
City where a man aged 40 hides a secret.
Filming took place in Los Angeles and San Fernando Valley,
California, from January to April 2005.
The film was released theatrically in the United States on August 19, 2005, by Universal
Pictures, and grossed over $177 million worldwide on a $26 million budget.
Critical reviews were generally positive, with praise for Carell's performance and the film's well-meaning
yet bawdy humor, which was a point of contention by some conservative commentators as well.
He won accolades from the Golden Schmoes Awards and MTV Movie & TV Awards for his role while Keener
received awards from the Boston Society of Film Critics and Los Angeles Film Critics Association.
The 40-Year-Old Virgin was named by the American Film
Institute one of 2005's Top 10 Films.
The film explores themes of first time, virgin, male
friendship, co-workers relationship, poker game.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.